联系方式

www.linkedin.com/in/lavinia-yang (LinkedIn)

热门技能

Python
Data Science
Machine Learning

Languages

中国語 (Native or Bilingual) 日本語 (Full Professional) 英語 (Full Professional)

Certifications

Certified ScrumMaster Certified Fraud Examiner 日本語能力試験 N1 DELF A2

Honors-Awards

Transaction Prediction

Silver Medal, Microsoft Malware Prediction on Kaggle (Top 0.2%) 明治大学大学院院長賞 Silver Medal, Santander Customer

Lavinia Yang

Principal (Jr.) Data Scientist at McKinsey & Company 东京地区

个人简介

Junior Principal Data Scientist in McKinsey & Company, over 10 years of experience pioneering AI solutions and driving enterprise-wide digital transformations. Combining deep expertise in ML/DL/Gen AI area and Full stack web application development to solve complex business problems for clients across various industry (Life Science & Pharmaceuticals, Energy, Retail, Automotive etc.) Successfully implemented 3 Enterprise-product level Gen AI solutions, including different types as RAG(Retrieval Augmented Generation), Conversational Agents, Copilot and Duets, achieved widespread adoption with 30,000+ active users across the organization.

ex Manager at PwC Japan, managed PwC Japan Al Lab, Forensic Technology Solutions | Power Market Analysis | Fraud Risk Detection

工作经历

McKinsey & Company Principal (Jr.) Data Scientist 2022年11月 - Present (2年8个月) 日本 Tokyo 東京

- Industry: Life Science, Pharma & Bio Tech, Global Energy & Materials, Retail
- Practice: Pharma Omni-channel Optimization, Go-to-market Strategy, Marketing & Sales Growth Advanced Analytics, Generative AI, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, AI solutions etc.
- Successfully implemented 3 Enterprise-product level Gen Al solutions, including different types as RAG(Retrieval Augmented Generation), Conversational Agents, Copilot and Duets, achieved widespread adoption with 30,000+ active users across the organization.

PwC Japan

Manager - Al Lab and Data Analytics 2018年7月-2022年10月(4年4个月)

PwC xLos Al Lab Al experiment leader, Manager of Forensic Data Analytics

Works Applications Co., Ltd. Full-stack Engineer 2016年4月-2018年6月(2年3个月) Tokyo

- Managed a 3 members team, supported the base technology development of artificial intelligence ERP system HUE

教育经历

日本东京大学

Data Science · (2018 - 2019)

明治大学

Master of Commercial Science (2014 - 2016)

西安交通大学

Bachelor's degree · (2009 - 2013)